Journey under the sea in a magical adventure.
Barbie Fairytopia: Mermaidia is a animation, family,
adventure film directed by Walter P. Martishius.
In this animated follow-up to Fairytopia, Elina enlists the help of a mermaid, Nori, to save
her friend Nalu, a merman prince who has been captured by the wicked Laverna.
Elina (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Bibble / Fungus 1 & 2 (voice), played by Lee Tockar.
Fungus Maximus (voice), played by Christopher Gaze.
Laverna (voice), played by Kathleen Barr.
Nori (voice), played by Chiara Zanni.
Sea Butterfly (voice), played by Andrea Libman.
Barbie: Fairytopia is a 2005 animated fantasy film directed by Walter P.
Martishius and William Lau and written by Elise Allen and Diane Duane.
The film first premiered on 6 March 2005, before
releasing direct-to-video on VHS and DVD.
It was distributed internationally through Universal
Pictures Video and Entertainment Rights.
The fifth installment in the Barbie film series and the first to have an original
storyline, it is based on the Fairytopia Mattel toy line introduced in 2003.
The film follows Elina, a wingless flower fairy who goes on a journey to save
the enchanted land of Fairytopia from the evil fairy Laverna.
The film is followed by two sequels; Barbie: Mermaidia and Barbie Fairytopia: Magic of the
Rainbow and two spin-offs; Barbie: Mariposa and Barbie: Mariposa & the Fairy Princess.
The film explores themes of magic, fairy, mermaid,
based on toy, female protagonist.